Guide to the Hermann M. Biggs Memorial Hospital records, 1936-1956.
Biggs, Hermann M. Memorial Hospital records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hermann M. Biggs Memorial Hospital records, 1936-1956.
1727
Hermann M. Biggs Memorial Hospital.
26 cubic ft.5 volumes
Organizational records, correspondence, and scrapbooks.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, administrative papers, annual reports, records and logbooks, memoranda, statistical data, and a scrapbook of newspaper clippings pertaining to the operation of a tuberculosis sanatorium in Ithaca, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, administrative papers, annual reports, records and logbooks, memoranda, statistical data, and a scrapbook of newspaper clippings pertaining to the operation of a tuberculosis sanatorium in Ithaca, New York.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hermann M. Biggs Memorial Hospital.; Hermann M. Biggs Memorial Hospital.
Subjects:
Tuberculosis -- Hospitals and sanatoriums -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Sanatoriums -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Hospitals -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Hospitals; Sanatoriums; Tuberculosis -- Hospitals
Places:
Tompkins County (N.Y.) -- Health and hygiene.; New York (State) -- Ithaca; New York (State) -- Tompkins County
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Dr. N. Stanley Lincoln - applications, health department, inter-hospital memos, rehabilitations, 1940-1959 (Box 1)
- Departments in hospital (Dr. Deegan and Dr. Lincoln) Radiographer, and clinical photographer, routine admission x-ray program, 1940-1950 (Box 2)
- Departments in hospital (Dr. Deegan and Dr. Lincoln) Anesthetist and pharmacy, 1930-1949 (Box 3)
- Dr. Deegan personnel: personal, administrative, annual reports, economy commission, No Date (Box 4)
- Dr. Deegan, personnel, No Date (Box 5)
- Dr. Deegan, administrative, No Date (Box 6)
- Dr. Lincoln's files, A-Z; and miscellaneous material, 1936-1959 (Box 7)
- Dr. Plunkett's files, 1939-1955 (Box 8)
- Associations and chemotherapy, No Date (Box 9)
- Chemotherapy, associations, special nurses records, No Date (Box 10)
- County Tuberculosis and health association (Dr. Deegan and Dr. Lincoln). Reports regarding patients by county, 1942-1946 (Box 11)
- Case register analysis, E. Bosworth, operating manual, reports, 1949-1959 (Box 12)
- Works Progress Association, building and grounds, No Date (Box 13)
- Patient surgery (case studies) E.B. Bosworth, No Date (Box 14)
- Patients - students, No Date (Box 15)
- American Trudeau Society study, printed material, 1947-1949 (Box 16)
- Annual reports, No Date (Box 17)
- Student nurse records, tuberculosis statistical data for New York state, includes punch cards, No Date (Box 18)
- Patient material, No Date (Box 19)
- "Biggs-Eye View" hospital newspaper (not a complete run), 1947-1954 (Box 20)
- List of patients with tuberculosis in 8 counties., 1936-1955 (Box 21)
  Does not include patients listed on study cards. Includes instructions on how to read cards. A-L Series II
- Biggs Memorial hospital material including a list of patients who received anti-tuberculosis drugs, 1949-1960 (Box 22)
- List of patients with tuberculosis in 8 counties. M-Z Series II, 1936-1955 (Box 23)
- Employee cards on cases I-Z, 1936-1956 (Box 24)
- Register of tuberculosis patients in 8 counties, excluding active cases at close J-S., 1936-1955 (Box 25)
- Biggs memorial hospital material - received after history study index., No Date (Box 26)
- Anesthesia records. Study cards pathology in restricted specimens, employees - cards A-H, No Date (Box 27)
- Register of tuberculosis patients in 8 counties, A-I, No Date (Box 28)
- Student nurses and others vaccinated with B.C.G., 1948-1956 (Box 29)
- Biggs memorial hospital material including the Biggs/Mt Morris resection study thoracoplasty, No Date (Box 30)
- Log Book, No Date (Volume 1)
- Log Book, No Date (Volume 2)
- Log Book, No Date (Volume 3)
- Log Book, No Date (Volume 4)
- Scrapbook, No Date (Volume 5)